planetcalc.com 2019-06-12

# Privacy Policy

Updated on 05/25/2018

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or use services from planetcalc.com (the “Site”).

We collect and store different types of data depending on how you interact with the Site. We use three levels of interaction:

  * **Visitors** Visitors browse Site content without logging in. Learn more
  * **Users** Any visitor can become a user by registering and logging in, or by logging in using a social media account. Users have access to a personal section of the Site and can save calculations, post comments and embed Site calculators in their own sites using our special widgets. Learn more
  * **Authors** Any user can become an author by creating content for the Site, such as a calculator, a handbook or an article. All content is published under [Creative Commons Attribution/Share-Alike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en) license terms. Learn more

## Visitors

### Information We Collect

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, browser language and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically collected information as “Device Information”.

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

  * “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
  * “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, non-precise location information (e.g. country and city, derived from user IP), referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (e.g. by generating analytics about how our visitors browse and interact with the Site).

Log files data is aggregated and anonymized. We may share such aggregated and anonymized information with third parties, including but not limited to companies that buy our advertising services. Log files are deleted within five days of being produced as a result of interaction with the Site.

### Information Collected by Our Partners

Ads appearing on the Site may be delivered to visitors by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your device or computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non-personal identification information about you or others who use your device or computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver "targeted" or "personalized" advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you.

Some of the ads may be served by Google. You can learn more about how Google uses cookies for advertising by visiting: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>.

To serve ads for visitors from the European Union we have selected the following GDPR-compliant partners:

#### Can we use your data to tailor ads for you?

Yes, tailor ads for me

No, show only non-personalised ads

## Users

### Information We Collect

#### Site Registration

When you register on the Site, we collect certain information from you, including your name, email address, and, at your discretion, photo or avatar image.

#### Social Media Login

We support user login through social media accounts. If you log in to the Site using credentials of a third-party social network, you authorize us to collect your social network information, including your name, email address, and social network identifier.

#### Public Activities

"Public activities" are any actions you take on the Site that are designed to be visible to other visitors, including:

  * **Handbook data** The calculators on this Site can use data, stored in special tables, which we refer to as "handbooks". An example of such a handbook would be latitude and longitude of world cities. Users can submit, edit and translate such data
  * **Saved calculations** Users can save data they have entered into calculator's input fields in order to reuse it later or to share calculation details with others by sharing calculation's permanent link.
  * **Comments** Users can leave comments on site content.

Any information you disclose in your public activities, along with your user name, social network identifier, and any image or photo, becomes public. If you choose to engage in public activities, you should be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, collected and used by other visitors to the Site. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in the course of your public activities and we have no responsibility to publish, remove or edit any of your public activities.

#### Cookies

Our Site uses "cookies" to store user-session information after registration or login. You may choose not to accept Site cookies. If you do so, note that some parts of the Site, including the personal section of the Site and saved calculations, will not function.

Note that this option relates only to Site cookies used to track login and user interactions with the Site and does not affect third-party cookies used by our advertising partners mentioned above.

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personal information, including your registration details and saved calculations.

We may use your email address to send you notifications if you are subscribed to comments on certain content pages or important updates regarding the Site operations.

You can manage your subscriptions on comments on your user settings page at My subscriptions.

### How Can Users Change or Control What is Collected?

You can delete submitted handbook data on the handbook data editor page.

You can delete any saved calculation from the main page of the personal section of the Site. Permanent links to such calculations will no longer be valid.

You can delete any posted comment on a related content page.

You can request erasure of your account and related data by contacting us at [privacy@planetcalc.com](mailto:privacy@planetcalc.com). Your account and data will be deleted within two weeks from the date of the request.

### Information We Collect

Authors can publish on the Site any created content, including calculators, articles, handbooks and translations of existing content to other languages (to be referred to as "Content"). Content becomes public and may be used under the terms of the [Creative Commons Attribution/Share-Alike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en).

Note that any information you disclose in your Content, along with your user name and any image or photo, becomes public. You should be aware that any personal information you disclose can be read, collected and used by other visitors to the Site. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to disclose in your Content and we have no responsibility to publish, remove or edit any of your Content.

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use your Content under the terms of the [Creative Commons Attribution/Share-Alike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en) license.

You also acknowledge that PLANETCALC has the right, using our sole discretion, to refuse to post or remove any Content that violates the Site Terms of usage, this privacy policy, or is otherwise objectionable or infringes the rights of others.

### How Can Authors Change or Control What is Collected?

You can delete any Content created by you from the personal section of the Site.

### Compliance with Legal Process

We may also share your personal information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

### Security of Your Personal Data

PLANETCALC adheres, by reasonable technical and organizational security protocols, to safeguard personal information that is submitted to us via our Site.

### Changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

### Getting in Touch

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at: [privacy@planetcalc.com](mailto:privacy@planetcalc.com).
